JEFF MICKLOS

Front-end developer who is well versed in the best practices of development, from conception to deployment. Keen eye for grid-based design and pixel perfect placement. A love for writing standards compliant code, which renders flawlessly across all browsers. Expertise in Javascript, including libraries, such as Prototype, Mootools and jQuery. Server-side programming skills that are fully realized within a user-centered environment.

Work Experience

Yelp - Front-End Software Engineer

http://yelp.com - June 2010 - Present

Worked on the front lines of local business review site, Yelp.com. Wrote and deployed (via Git) HTML, CSS, Javascript and Python in daily test driven iteration cycles. Led front-end efforts for local deals, advertising placements and internal applications.

- Acted as an internal evangelist for progressive enhancement by way of HTML5 and CSS3
- · Lead engineer on Yelp's new local deal feature, allowing users to purchase coupons for local business, i.e. Groupon
- · Lead designer on Yelp's Webkit-specific mobile site

Open Source Development

http://github.com/jeffmicklos

Contributed to multiple open source Javascript libraries by developing classes and plug-ins, including a YUI lightbox implementation and functional programming tools for jQuery. Built a Python class to export vendor-prefixed CSS3 properties.

Stollet - Chief Architect

http://stollet.com - November 2009 - May 2010

A design inspiration blog based on user generated content that gives users the ability to share bits and pieces of content from all around the web while looking good and keeping a fantastically lean HTTP footprint.

- An optimized custom PHP MVC framework allows for quick delivery to a large network
- Standard compliant XHTML/CSS is progressively enhanced with CSS3 and heavy DOM manipulation

Webtape - Chief Architect

http://onwebtape.com - November 2007 - Present

The site gives users the ability to upload photos, write blog entires, share Youtube (Vimeo or Viddler) videos and Flickr photos. Facebook integration via the PHP and Connect libraries give users the ability to share posts across both sites and allows Facebook users to comment on Webtape posts via open authentication (OAuth).

Education

Bachelor of Science - Web Design & Interactive Media

Art Institute of California - San Diego - October 2005 - June 2009

- Honors graduate
- · Graduating class speaker
- · Best graduate award winner
- Tutor for students in XHTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and MySQL